A Guide to the Foundation for Child Development records FA019
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Grant Programs, 1911, 1946-1996, bulk 1960-1996; bulk; 4
  - General Grants, 1976-1995; 4
    - New York Association for the Learning Disabled, 1982-1984 (Reel 80, Frame 572)
    - New York City Citizens' Coalition for Children, 1984-1986 (Reel 80, Frame 613)
    - New York City Criminal Justice Agency, 1981, 1985, 1988 (Reel 80, Frame 645)
    - New York City Education Project, 1980-1981 (Reel 80, Frame 843)
    - New York City Education Seminar and Policy Studies Project, 1976-1978 (Reel 80, Frame 898)
    - New York City School Volunteer Program, 1983-1985 (Reel 80, Frame 1022)
    - New York Community Trust, 1987 (Reel 80, Frame 1044)
    - New York Community Trust, 1988-1989 (Reel 81, Frame 1)
    - New York Community Trust, 1990 (Reel 81, Frame 308)
    - New York Community Trust, 1991 (Reel 81, Frame 606)
    - New York Community Trust, 1992 (Reel 81, Frame 851)
    - New York Community Trust Summer Program, 1986-1987 (Reel 81, Frame 982)
    - New York Council on Adoptable Children, 1984-1985 (Reel 81, Frame 1002)
    - New York Grantmakers Summer Program for Youth, 1984-1985, 1987-1989 (Reel 81, Frame 1025)
    - New York Regional Association of Grantmakers, 1979-1984 (Reel 82, Frame 1)
    - New York Regional Association of Grantmakers, 1986-1990 (Reel 82, Frame 167)
    - New York Regional Association of Grantmakers, 1991-1994 (Reel 82, Frame 355)
    - New York Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children, 1991-1993 (Reel 82, Frame 525)
    - New York State Bar Association, 1981-1983 (Reel 82, Frame 624)
    - New York State Child Care Coordinating Council, 1989-1993 (Reel 82, Frame 848)
    - New York State Council on Children and Families, 1980, 1982, 1985 (Reel 83, Frame 1)
    - New York State Council on Children and Families, 1987, 1989-1993 (Reel 83, Frame 239)
    - New York State Department of Social Services, 1987-1988, 1991 (Reel 83, Frame 469)
    - New York University Graduate School of School Work, 1978-1979, 1982, 1984-1985 (Reel 83, Frame 801)
    - North Carolina Children's Index, 1984-1989 (Reel 83, Frame 895)
    - Northern Carolina Grantmakers, 1987 (Reel 83, Frame 924)
    - Northside Center for Child Development, Inc., 1986-1992 (Reel 83, Frame 934)
    - The Nova Institute, Inc., 1983 (Reel 83, Frame 989)
    - Parent Action, 1991-1993 (Reel 83, Frame 1026)
    - Pennsylvania State University, 1985-1987-1989-1991 (Reel 84, Frame 1)
    - Planned Parenthood of New York City, Inc., 1990-1992 (Reel 84, Frame 40)
    - Population Resource Center, 1990-1991 (Reel 84, Frame 71)
    - Public Action Coalition on Toys, 1974-1982 (Reel 84, Frame 175)
    - Public Education Association, 1981-1984, 1986-1987 (Reel 84, Frame 446)
    - The Research Foundation for Mental Hygiene, Inc., 1989-1992 (Reel 84, Frame 690)
    - The Research Foundation of the State University of New York, 1990-1993 (Reel 84, Frame 760)
    - Resources for Children with Special Needs, Inc., 1985, 1988, 1990 (Reel 84, Frame 1032)
    - Resources for Children with Special Needs, Inc., 1991-1993 (Reel 85, Frame 1)
    - Rheedlen Foundation, Inc., 1991 (Reel 85, Frame 334)
    - Riverdale Children's Association, 1979-1982 (Reel 85, Frame 357)
    - Riverdale Neighborhood Home, 1989 (Reel 85, Frame 519)
    - School and Business Alliance of New York, Inc., 1988-1990 (Reel 85, Frame 533)
    - Scientists' Institute for Public Information, 1990-1991 (Reel 85, Frame 577)
    - M. Brewster Smith - Belding Scholar, 1981-1984 (Reel 85, Frame 677)
    - Social Science Research Council, 1976-1979 (Reel 85, Frame 735)
    - Social Science Research Council, 1980-1982 (Reel 86, Frame 1)
    - Social Science Research Council, 1983-1985 (Reel 86, Frame 268)
    - Social Science Research Council - Center for Coordination of Research on Social Indicators - Child and Family Indicators Advisory Group, 1979-1982 (Reel 86, Frame 591)
    - Social Science Research Council - Committee for Research on the Urban Underclass, 1988-1989 (Reel 86, Frame 690)
    - Social Science Research Council - New York City Area Study, 1983-1984 (Reel 86, Frame 761)
    - Social Science Research Council - Subcommittee on Child Development in Life-Span Perspective, 1981-1984 (Reel 86, Frame 792)
    - Social Science Research Council - Subcommittee on Child Development in Life-Span Perspective, 1985-1987 (Reel 86, Frame 1029)
    - Social Science Research Council - Undergraduate Training and Research on Family Poverty and Child Development, 1989 (Reel 87, Frame 1)
    - Social Science Research Council - Undergraduate Training and Research on Family Poverty and Child Development, 1990 (Reel 87, Frame 118)
    - Social Science Research Council - Undergraduate Training and Research on Family Poverty and Child Development, 1991, 1993 (Reel 87, Frame 323)
    - Society for Research in Child Development - Committee on Summer Institute and Study Group, 1975-1980 (Reel 87, Frame 422)
    - Society for Research in Child Development - Committee on Summer Institute and Study Group, 1981-1984 (Reel 87, Frame 723)
    - Society for Research in Child Development - Committee on Summer Institute and Study Group, 1985-1988 (Reel 87, Frame 1000)
    - Society for Research in Child Development - Congressional Science Fellowships in Child Development, 1980-1982 (Reel 88, Frame 1)
    - Society for Research in Child Development - Congressional Science Fellowships in Child Development, 1983 (Reel 88, Frame 425)
    - Society for Research in Child Development - Congressional Science Fellowships in Child Development, 1984-1986 (Reel 88, Frame 801)
    - Society for Research in Child Development - Congressional Science Fellowships in Child Development, 1987-1989 (Reel 89, Frame 1)
    - Society for Research in Child Development - Congressional Science Fellowships in Child Development - Applications, 1981-1982 (Reel 89, Frame 272)
    - Society for Research in Child Development - Congressional Science Fellowships in Child Development - Applications, 1986-1988 (Reel 89, Frame 585)
    - Society for Research in Child Development - Congressional Science Fellowships in Child Development - Child Development Seminar for Congressional Fellows, 1981-1985 (Reel 89, Frame 686)
      - Wye Conference, 1982 (Reel 89, Frame 838)
    - Society for Research in Child Development - Congressional Science Fellowships in Child Development - Finalists, 1983-1984 (Reel 89, Frame 856)
    - Society for Research in Child Development - Congressional Science Fellowships in Child Development - Questionnaire, 1979-1981 (Reel 90, Frame 1)
    - Society for Research in Child Development - Continuity of Care: A Guide to Social Programs, 1983 (Reel 90, Frame 199)
    - Society for Research in Child Development - Publication - Child Development Research and Social Policy, 1979-1986 (Reel 90, Frame 332)
    - Society for Research in Child Development - Summer Institutes on Child Development and Social Policy, 1984 (Reel 90, Frame 451)
    - Society for Research in Child Development - Summer Institutes on Child Development and Social Policy, 1985 (Reel 90, Frame 580)
    - Society for Research in Child Development - Summer Institutes on Child Development and Social Policy, 1986-1990 (Reel 90, Frame 930)
    - State Communities Aid Association, 1988-1989 (Reel 91, Frame 1)
    - State-based Child Advocacy, Inc., 1988-1991 (Reel 91, Frame 112)
    - Statewide Youth Advocacy, Inc., 1977, 1981-1983 (Reel 91, Frame 288)
    - Statewide Youth Advocacy, Inc., 1985-1986 (Reel 91, Frame 560)
    - Statewide Youth Advocacy, 1987-1993 (Reel 91, Frame 896)
    - Task Force on Permanency Planning for Foster Children, Inc., 1987-1991 (Reel 92, Frame 1)
    - Teachers College, Columbia University, 1991-1993 (Reel 92, Frame 311)
    - Twin Cities Public Television, 1983-1984 (Reel 92, Frame 347)
    - United Hospital Fund, 1987-1991 (Reel 92, Frame 360)
    - United Neighborhood Houses of New York, Inc., 1988-1990 (Reel 92, Frame 494)
    - United Parents Association of New York, Inc. - Educational Priorities Panel, 1984, 1986-1988 (Reel 92, Frame 592)
    - University of Arkansas at Little Rock, 1983-1985 (Reel 92, Frame 730)
    - University of California, Berkeley, 1980-1983, 1987 (Reel 92, Frame 869)
    - University of California, Davis, 1979-1982 (Reel 92, Frame 894)
    - University of Chicago, 1987-1988 (Reel 93, Frame 1)
    - University of Chicago, 1992-1995 (Reel 93, Frame 74)
    - University of Kansas, Lawrence, 1987-1988 (Reel 93, Frame 245)
    - University of Massachusetts Medical School, 1987-1988 (Reel 93, Frame 283)
    - University of Massachusetts Medical School, 1989-1992 (Reel 93, Frame 599)
    - University of Medicine and Dentistry of New Jersey, Rutgers Medical School, 1987-1989 (Reel 93, Frame 780)
    - University of Michigan, 1980-1987 (Reel 93, Frame 882)
    - University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, 1984-1986 (Reel 93, Frame 1022)
    - University of Pennsylvania, 1980, 1983 (Reel 93, Frame 1045)
    - University of Rochester, 1984-1987 (Reel 94, Frame 1)
    - University of Virginia, Charlottesville, 1986-1989 (Reel 94, Frame 64)
    - University of Wisconsin, Madison, 1979-1982 (Reel 94, Frame 103)
    - University of Wisconsin - Dissertation - 'Adolescent Motherhood: Social Support and Parenting' - Maxine Seaborn Thompson, 1982 (Reel 94, Frame 323)
    - Vanderbilt University, 1980-1983 (Reel 94, Frame 664)
    - Welfare Research, Inc., 1985 (Reel 94, Frame 905)
    - Welfare Research, Inc., 1986 (Reel 94, Frame 988)
    - Welfare Research, Inc., 1987-1988 (Reel 95, Frame 1)
    - Yale Bush Center, 1987-1988 (Reel 95, Frame 158)
    - Youth Law Center, 1988-1989 (Reel 95, Frame 219)
    - Youth Law Center, 1990 (Reel 95, Frame 439)
  - State of the Child Program, 1960-1981; 5
    Two studies which were developed in New York City and carried out during the 1960s and 1970s concerning children and families were incorporated into the program known as "State of the Child: New York City I and II." Data was collected that focused upon children's health, involvement in school, and the family and communities in which they lived, with the intent of describing the quality of life of the over 2 million children living in New York City at that time and, particularly, those at risk. Using publicly distributed statistics, this pioneering effort to develop a measurable "State of the Child" included child-rearing, income distribution, and services provided by public and voluntary institutions. The emphasis was placed upon what was termed as "applied social indicators" to answer questions regarding the success of school reading programs, health services, children's safety during that time and in the decade or two prior to the study. Program "monitors" in place attempted to recommend improvements in services through monitoring, particularly the child health stations, public school attendance program, food programs in the public schools, and school bilingual programs.
    The State of the Child reports and related memoranda are found on reels 99-100.
    - Series 4.5 - Grant Programs - State of the Child Program, 1960-1981 (Reel 95, Frame 680)
    - Abortion, 1960-1979 (Reel 95, Frame 681)
    - Agency for Child Development, 1978-1979 (Reel 95, Frame 755)
    - Attendance, 1974-1979 (Reel 95, Frame 871)
    - Basic Competency Test, 1977-1979 (Reel 96, Frame 1)
    - Bilingual Education, 1976-1979 (Reel 96, Frame 54)
    - Births, 1978-1979 (Reel 96, Frame 175)
    - Census Data, 1976-1978 (Reel 96, Frame 186)
    - Child Abuse Data, 1976, 1978-1980 (Reel 96, Frame 300)
    - Children Away from Home, 1978-1980 (Reel 96, Frame 453)
    - Children's Budgets, 1977-1981 (Reel 96, Frame 548)
    - Class Size, 1977-1978 (Reel 96, Frame 728)
    - Comptroller's Reports, 1978 (Reel 96, Frame 789)
    - Child Welfare Information Services, Inc. - Reports, 1977-1978 (Reel 96, Frame 940)
    - Department of Health - Division of Day Care, 1978 (Reel 97, Frame 1)
    - Division of Youth and Court Process, 1974-1980 (Reel 97, Frame 6)
    - Divorce, 1968-1979 (Reel 97, Frame 101)
    - Drop-Outs, 1976-1977, 1979 (Reel 97, Frame 129)
    - Education, 1975-1979 (Reel 97, Frame 283)
    - Economic and Demographic Trends, 1957-1980 (Reel 97, Frame 440)
    - Enrollment in Public and Non-Public Schools, 1978-1979 (Reel 97, Frame 578)
    - Ethnic Distribution in Public Schools, 1957-1979 (Reel 97, Frame 602)
    - Ethnic Enrollment, 1977-1979 (Reel 97, Frame 916)
    - Family Budgets, 1969-1979 (Reel 97, Frame 1004)
    - Family Court, 1976-1978 (Reel 97, Frame 1068)
    - Fertility Rates, 1960-1980 (Reel 98, Frame 1)
    - Foster Care, 1976-1979 (Reel 98, Frame 39)
    - Foster Care Cost, 1976-1977 (Reel 98, Frame 163)
    - Graduates and Competency, 1978-1979 (Reel 98, Frame 209)
    - Health Care Status for Low Income Families, 1974-1975, 1977 (Reel 98, Frame 341)
    - Health Statistics, 1974-1975, 1977-1979 (Reel 98, Frame 505)
    - Immunization, 1977-1979 (Reel 98, Frame 569)
    - Kindergarten Enrollment, 1970-1978 (Reel 98, Frame 693)
    - Lead Poisoning, 1975, 1977-1979 (Reel 98, Frame 709)
    - Long-term Residential Child Care, 1975-1977 (Reel 98, Frame 831)
    - New York City School Health Curriculum Project, 1977-1981 (Reel 98, Frame 982)
    - Nutrition, 1978-1979 (Reel 99, Frame 1)
    - Pre-school Enrollment, 1969-1978 (Reel 99, Frame 124)
    - Public Assistance, 1976-1979 (Reel 99, Frame 242)
    - Publicity, 1975-1976 (Reel 99, Frame 303)
    - Public's Attitudes Toward the Public Schools, 1976-1978, 1980 (Reel 99, Frame 334)
    - Reading Achievement, 1978-1979 (Reel 99, Frame 371)
    - Scholastic Aptitude Test Scores, 1977-1979 (Reel 99, Frame 443)
    - School Crime, 1977-1979 (Reel 99, Frame 470)
    - School Lunch, 1978-1979 (Reel 99, Frame 584)
    - School Grade Promotions, 1978-1979 (Reel 99, Frame 683)
    - Special Education, 1975-1979 (Reel 99, Frame 705)
    - State of the Child Draft Report, 1974 (Reel 99, Frame 860)
    - State of the Child Report - Cover Material and Costs, 1975-1976 (Reel 99, Frame 1019)
    - State of the Child Report - Memoranda, 1976 (Reel 99, Frame 1041)
    - State of the Child Report - Memoranda, 1977 (Reel 100, Frame 1)
    - State of the Child Report - Memoranda, 1978 (Reel 100, Frame 294)
    - State of the Child Report - Memoranda, 1979-1980 (Reel 100, Frame 474)
    - State of the Child Report: New York City '79, 1975-1981 (Reel 100, Frame 544)
    - State of the Child Report - Press Conference, May 26, 1976 (Reel 100, Frame 852)
    - State of the Child Report - Public Relations Effort, 1976 (Reel 100, Frame 1083)
    - Suspensions, 1974-1979 (Reel 101, Frame 1)
    - Teachers, 1976-1979 (Reel 101, Frame 118)
    - Teenage Pregnancy, 1978, 1981 (Reel 101, Frame 243)
    - Test Scores, 1976-1979 (Reel 101, Frame 366)
    - Vandalism Replacement Costs, 1979 (Reel 101, Frame 386)
    - Victim Services Agency, 1979 (Reel 101, Frame 392)
    - Working Mothers, 1973-1978 (Reel 101, Frame 433)
  - Young Scholars Program, 1982-1991; 6
    Sub-subseries 1 - Declinations
    Sub-subseries 2 - Research Projects
    This Foundation program supported research by "young scholars" on the "social and affective development of children." This program was to aid in the development of career goals for post-doctoral researchers in childhood development.
    - Declinations, 1983-1984; 1
      Applicants denied grant awards for the Young Scholars Program during 1983-1984 are alphabetically ordered in this subseries.
      Online access to these materials is restricted because copyright for these materials is held by the grant applicant.
      - Series 4.61 - Grant Programs - Young Scholars Program - Declinations, 1983-1984 (Reel 101, Frame 540)
      - Young Scholars Program, 1981-1982, 1989 (Reel 101, Frame 541)
      - Lawrence Aber, 1984 (Reel 101, Frame 563)
      - Gary Adams and Keith Lenz, 1983 (Reel 101, Frame 648)
      - Maria Allison, 1983 (Reel 101, Frame 686)
      - Wayne Alves, 1983-1984 (Reel 101, Frame 726)
      - Marilyn J. Aten, 1983-1984 (Reel 101, Frame 775)
      - Jay Belsky, 1983-1984 (Reel 101, Frame 812)
      - Judith Blakemore, 1983-1984 (Reel 101, Frame 854)
      - Karen Blum, 1983-1984 (Reel 101, Frame 884)
      - Ann Boggiano, 1983-1984 (Reel 101, Frame 916)
      - Leslie Brody, 1983-1984 (Reel 101, Frame 952)
      - Phyllis Bronstein, 1983 (Reel 101, Frame 988)
      - Brant Burleson, 1983-1984 (Reel 101, Frame 1020)
      - Irene Burtchen, 1983-1984 (Reel 101, Frame 1061)
      - David Buss and Kathleen McCartney, 1983-1984 (Reel 101, Frame 1077)
      - Ray Buss, 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 1)
      - Kay Bussey, 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 33)
      - David Cantor, 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 54)
      - Ida Cardone and Joanne Householder, 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 85)
      - D. Bruce Carter, 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 154)
      - Patrick Casey, 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 187)
      - Moon Ja Chung (Ineligible), 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 232)
      - Reginald Clark, 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 254)
      - Douglas Clements, 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 286)
      - Nancy Close and Donald Cohen, undated (Reel 102, Frame 327)
      - Pamela Cole, 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 352)
      - Patricia Crittenden, 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 389)
      - Patricia Davis and Flora Cherry, 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 422)
      - Marilyn Denninger, 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 476)
      - Cathy Dent, 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 501)
      - Dobay Dezso, 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 532)
      - Kim Dolgin, 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 562)
      - Mary Dozier, 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 591)
      - Carl J. Dunst, 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 619)
      - Warren Eaton, 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 660)
      - Karen Ebeling, 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 687)
      - Pamela Elizabeth, 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 720)
      - Mary Ann Evans, 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 780)
      - Francesca Emiliani, 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 787)
      - Martin Ford, 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 812)
      - Ellice Ann Forman, 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 841)
      - Aldo Fortunati, 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 878)
      - Patricia Francis, 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 911)
      - Evelyn Freeman, 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 937)
      - Lucia French, 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 968)
      - Juarlyn Gaiter, 1983 (Reel 102, Frame 997)
      - Eugene C. Goldfield, 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 1024)
      - James Green, 1983-1984 (Reel 102, Frame 1056)
      - Gwen Gustafson, 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 1)
      - Amy Halberstadt, 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 35)
      - Lawrence D. Hammer, 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 82)
      - Carol Harding, 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 113)
      - Robert Harrington, 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 142)
      - Daniel Hart, 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 174)
      - Katherine Hildebrandt, 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 206)
      - Timothy Hill, 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 240)
      - Susan Holloway, 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 271)
      - Carollee Howes, 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 314)
      - Elizabeth J. Hrncir, 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 360)
      - Arminta Jacobson, 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 397)
      - Paul Janos, 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 427)
      - Luis Joyce-Moniz, 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 472)
      - Audrey Kast, 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 490)
      - Susan P. Keane, 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 512)
      - Margaret A. King, 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 547)
      - George Knight, 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 575)
      - Rona Knight, 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 610)
      - Marta Korintus, 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 679)
      - Peter La Freniere, 1984 (Reel 103, Frame 697)
      - Michelle Lampl, 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 732)
      - Daniel Lapsley, 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 756)
      - Julie A. Larrieu, 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 796)
      - Robert Larzelere, 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 846)
      - Alain Legendre, 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 882)
      - Jacqueline Lerner, 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 917)
      - Florence Levy (Ineligible), 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 950)
      - Patricia Linn, 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 979)
      - Ruth Linn, 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 1015)
      - Deanna Livingstone, 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 1047)
      - Douglas Longshore, 1983-1984 (Reel 103, Frame 1083)
      - Susan L. McBride, 1983-1984 (Reel 104, Frame 1)
      - Kevin MacDonald, 1983-1984 (Reel 104, Frame 27)
      - Sharie McNamee (Ineligible), 1983-1984 (Reel 104, Frame 67)
      - Carol Martin and Merry Bullock, 1983-1984 (Reel 104, Frame 103)
      - Linda C. Mayes, 1983-1984 (Reel 104, Frame 147)
      - C. Julius Meisel, 1983-1984 (Reel 104, Frame 178)
      - Gale Morrison, 1983-1984 (Reel 104, Frame 210)
      - Lois Muir, 1983-1984 (Reel 104, Frame 257)
      - Charles Nelson, 1983-1984 (Reel 104, Frame 285)
      - Robert Noll, 1983-1984 (Reel 104, Frame 311)
      - Aimee Nover, 1983-1984 (Reel 104, Frame 347)
      - Samuel L. Odom, 1983-1984 (Reel 104, Frame 377)
      - Martin Packer, 1983-1984 (Reel 104, Frame 410)
      - David Pellegrini, 1983-1984 (Reel 104, Frame 446)
      - Erin Phelps, 1983-1984 (Reel 104, Frame 488)
      - Lillian Phenice and Marjorie Kostelnik, 1983-1984 (Reel 104, Frame 526)
      - James Plunkett, 1983-1984 (Reel 104, Frame 595)
      - Susan Price, 1983-1984 (Reel 104, Frame 623)
      - Adele Proctor, 1983-1984 (Reel 104, Frame 657)
      - John Reisman, 1983-1984 (Reel 104, Frame 693)
      - K. Ann Renninger, 1983-1984 (Reel 104, Frame 726)
      - Amy Richman, 1983-1984 (Reel 104, Frame 763)
      - Doreen Ridgeway, 1983-1984 (Reel 104, Frame 821)
      - Joann Robinson, 1983-1984 (Reel 104, Frame 858)
      - Peter Rosenbaum, 1980-1984 (Reel 104, Frame 879)
      - Ken Rotenberg, 1983-1984 (Reel 104, Frame 918)
      - Fred Rothbaum, 1983-1984 (Reel 104, Frame 956)
      - Catherine Scanlon, 1983-1984 (Reel 104, Frame 1007)
      - W. George Scarlett, 1983-1984 (Reel 104, Frame 1037)
      - David A. Schuldberg, 1983-1984 (Reel 104, Frame 1077)
      - Linda J. Shope, 1983-1984 (Reel 105, Frame 1)
      - Wendy Silverman, 1983-1984 (Reel 105, Frame 35)
      - Arietta Slade, 1983-1984 (Reel 105, Frame 93)
      - Susan Spieker, 1983-1984 (Reel 105, Frame 127)
      - Deborah J. Stipek, 1983-1984 (Reel 105, Frame 152)
      - Margaret Sullivan, 1983-1984 (Reel 105, Frame 184)
      - Naoto Suzuki, 1983-1984 (Reel 105, Frame 225)
      - Bill Thornton and Richard Ryckman, 1983-1984 (Reel 105, Frame 254)
      - Dale Ulrich, 1983-1984 (Reel 105, Frame 292)
      - Elizabeth Van Tassel, 1983-1984 (Reel 105, Frame 326)
      - Patricia Van West, 1983-1984 (Reel 105, Frame 352)
      - Brian Vandenberg, 1983-1984 (Reel 105, Frame 388)
      - Tedra Walden, 1983-1984 (Reel 105, Frame 414)
      - Mary Ward, 1983-1984 (Reel 105, Frame 449)
      - Allan Wigfield, 1983-1984 (Reel 105, Frame 481)
      - John Worobey, 1983-1984 (Reel 105, Frame 515)
      - Phylllis Zelkowitz, 1983-1984 (Reel 105, Frame 551)
      - Patricia Zukow, 1983-1984 (Reel 105, Frame 579)
    - Research Projects, 1982-1991; 2
      Individual researcher project reports are alphabetically ordered within this subseries. The folder for Linda Michalson, 1983 was missing at the time of filming.
      - Series 4.62 - Grant Programs - Young Scholars Program - Research Projects, 1982-1991 (Reel 105, Frame 622)
      - Teresa M. Amabile, 1984 (Reel 105, Frame 623)
      - R. Christopher Barden, 1984 (Reel 105, Frame 629)
      - Celia A. Brownell, 1984-1986 (Reel 105, Frame 669)
      - William M. Bukowski, 1984-1985 (Reel 105, Frame 709)
      - Dante Cicchetti, 1982-1984 (Reel 105, Frame 736)
      - Deborah L. Coates, 1983-1984 (Reel 105, Frame 943)
      - Cynthia Garcia Coll, 1983, 1987 (Reel 105, Frame 1005)
      - James P. Connell, 1983-1986 (Reel 105, Frame 1065)